Esta lição 26 de Pimsleur Inglês 1.
Listen to this conversation. Katie acaba de reconhecer o seu amigo Carlos na
rua. Carlos, wait! Where are you going?
I'm going to the department store on Park Avenue. Why?
Because I want to buy something for my wife. Do you know what time it
is? Are the stores open? Yes, they are. It's not too late.
It's only eight o'clock. Thanks. Goodbye,
Katie. Goodbye, Carlos. Nesta conversa,
a mulher disse: It's only eight o'clock. O que quer dizer? São só
oito horas. Listen again. Carlos,
wait! Where are you going? I'm going to the department store on Park
Avenue. Why? Because I want to buy something for my wife.
Do you know what time it is? Are the stores open?
Yes, they are. It's not too late. It's only eight o'clock.
Thanks. Goodbye, Katie. Goodbye, Carlos.
Now answer the questions. Agora responda as
perguntas. Now answer the questions. Hello,
how are you today?
I'm fine.
I'm fine, thanks.
How's your wife? Is she fine?
Yes, she's fine too.
My wife's fine too, thank you.
Ask. E você, como vai?
And you? How are you?
Como ela diz? Ah, eu não sei.
Oh, I don't know.
Ask por quê?
Why? Why? Porque eu
gostaria de comprar algo.
Because I'd like to buy something.
E eu não posso.
And I can't.
And I can't. Try to
ask. Por que não?
Why not? Why not?
Porque as lojas estão fechadas.
Because the stores are closed.
The stores are closed.
Verdade.
Really? Sim, elas estão
fechadas.
Yes, they're closed.
É tarde.
It's late. It's late. É tarde
demais. It's too
late.
It's too late.
Mas elas estão abertas amanhã.
But they're open tomorrow.
Try to say, "Elas estão abertas tarde amanhã." They're
open late tomorrow.
They're open late tomorrow.
Você pode comprar algo amanhã.
You can buy something tomorrow.
Em uma loja de departamentos.
In a department store.
O que você quer comprar?
What do you want to buy?
Sai, meu marido quer comprar algo.
My husband wants to buy something.
Para nossa menina pequena.
For our little girl.
Try to say. Então vá para a loja de departamentos.
Then go to the department store.
The department store.
Na Avenida Parque.
On Park Avenue.
Amanhã as lojas estão abertas.
Tomorrow the stores are open.
Ask where Park Avenue is. Ask where Park Avenue
is.
Where's Park Avenue?
Fica lá.
It's over there.
Vá para a direita.
Go to the right.
Depois para a esquerda.
Then to the left.
To the left. Sei.
Meu marido precisa de um pouco de dinheiro.
My husband needs some money.
Needs. My husband needs some
money. Eu também
preciso de um pouco de dinheiro.
I need some money too.
Por quê? Why?
Porque eu vou para Washington, D.C. Washington,
D.C. Escute e repita parte por parte.
D.C.
Washington.
Ton, ton,
ing,
wash. Washington.
Washington, D.C.
Washington, D.C. D.C. significa District of Columbia,
o que quer dizer Distrito da Colúmbia. Isto distingue
a capital do estado com o mesmo nome. Agora diga: por
que eu vou para Washington, D.C.?
Because I'm going to Washington, D.C.
D.C.
Washington, D.C.
I'm going
to Washington,
D.C. Sem mudar a ordem das palavras, pergunte: Você vai para Washington?
You're going to Washington.
O que você vai fazer lá? Listen and repeat.
What are you going to do there?
There.
There. Você já usou
there antes nas expressões there are,
over there. Quando a palavra é usada sozinha, quer dizer
naquele lugar. Pergunte outra vez: o que você vai fazer
What are you going to do there?
Você quer dizer eu vou ver uns amigos. Primeiro,
uns amigos. Listen and repeat. Some friends.
Friends. Friends.
Some friends.
Say again. Uns amigos.
Eu vou ver. Listen and repeat. I'm going
to see.
See. See. To see.
I'm going to see.
How do you say?
To see. See.
To see. Say,
eu vou ver.
I'm going to see.
Eu vou ver uns amigos.
I'm going to see some friends.
In Washington,
D.C. In Washington, D.C.
In Washington, D.C.
alguns amigos. Listen and repeat. A few
friends.
Few. A few.
A few friends.
Say again. Alguns amigos.
Por falar em Washington, diga: eu tenho alguns amigos lá.
I have a few friends there.
E eu vou trabalhar. Listen and repeat.
And I'm going to work.
Work. To work.
I'm going to work.
Ask her if she's going to work.
Are you going to work?
Um pouco. A little.
Eu vou ver uns amigos.
I'm going to see some friends.
Some friends. Eu vou
ver meus amigos.
I'm going to see my friends.
My friends. E eu
vou trabalhar.
And I'm going to work. And I'm going to
work. Try to say: Eu vou trabalhar um pouco.
I'm going to work a little.
E eu vou ver alguns amigos.
And I'm going to see a few friends.
Talvez. Listen and repeat. Maybe.
B.
May. Maybe. Você vai trabalhar?
Are you going to work?
Talvez.
Maybe.
Maybe. Sim,
eu acho que sim. Listen and repeat. Yes, I think so.
So. Think.
Think. Think so.
Think so.
I think so.
Yes, I think so.
In English, how do you say "Eu acho que sim"?
I think so.
Now try to say "Eu acho que não." I
don't think so.
I don't think so.
Agora pergunte-lhe se ela vai ver George.
Are you going to see George?
George? Are you going
to see George?
Eu acho que não.
I don't think so.
Talvez. Maybe.
Maybe. Now try to ask
if George works in Washington.
Does George work in Washington?
Eu acho que sim, mas eu não sei.
I think so, but I don't know.
Agora tente perguntar se ela vai ver Charles.
Are you going to see Charles?
Como ela responde? Não, eu acho que não.
No, I don't think so.
Talvez. Maybe.
Maybe. Try to say,
Charles trabalha em Nova York.
Charles works in New York.
Works. Charles works in New York.
Diga que
você acha que não.
I don't think so.
Try to say: Eu acho que ele trabalha em Nova York.
I think he works in New York.
Try to say, "Ele mora em Nova York." He
lives in New York.
He lives. Eu acho
que ele mora em Nova York.
I think he lives in New York.
Ask. Então você vai ver Mary.
Then are you going to see Mary?
Say, talvez. Maybe.
Diga que você acha que sim.
I think so.
Eu acho que eu vou ver Mary.
I think I'm going to see Mary.
Mas eu também vou trabalhar.
But I'm going to work too.
E eu vou ver alguns amigos.
And I'm going to see a few friends.
I'm going to see a few friends.
Say, por favor me dê.
Please give me.
Try to say alguns dólares.
A few dollars.
Please give me a few dollars.
Por quê? Why?
Porque eu vou para Washington, D.C.
Because I'm going to Washington, D.C.
Washington é caro.
Washington is expensive.
Try to say, minha amiga Mary.
My friend Mary.
Por falar em Washington, diga: minha amiga Mary mora lá.
My friend Mary lives there.
Ela trabalha lá.
She works there.
Quão longe fica Washington?
How far is Washington?
How far
is Washington?
Oitenta milhas. 80 miles.
It's 80 miles.
Você vai hoje?
Are you going today?
Eu não sei, talvez.
I don't know, maybe.
Eu acho que não.
I don't think so.
Mas eu gostaria de ver Washington.
But I'd like to see Washington.
And I have
some friends there.
Some friends.
Agora imagine que você está indo para Washington. Pare para pedir informações.
Pergunte se é esta estrada para Washington, D.C.
Is this the road to Washington, D.C.?
No, the road you want is to the right. Você não ouviu
bem o que ela disse. Pergunte: à esquerda?
To the left?
No, go to the right and then straight ahead.
Você quer fazer compras ao chegar. Pergunte: As
lojas de departamentos estão abertas agora?
Are the department stores open now?
No, it's late. I think the department stores are closed.
Say that it's not late.
It's not late.
Como ela discordaria enfaticamente?
Yes, it is late.
Yes, it is.
E eu acho que as lojas estão fechadas.
And I think the stores are closed.
Nesta lição de inglês um se incluem exercícios de leitura.